<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Repositories on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Modelling</title>
    <link>/tags/repositories/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Repositories on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Modelling</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/repositories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Access data in the Australian Mental Health Systems Models Dataverse Collection.</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/08/28/access_open_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/08/28/access_open_data/</guid>
      <description>1. Objectives In this tutorial we will:
Describe the knowedge, skills and software requirements for completing this tutorial;
Briefly describe the concepts relating to the Australian Mental Health Systems Models Dataverse repository; and
Outline the steps required to search for and download files contained in repository datasets using two alternative approaches;
Using a web based interface (very simple, suitable for low volume requests where reproducibility is not required); and Using R commands (an approach that requires a little more up-front learning, but which can be used in automated and reproducible workflows) 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australian Mental Health Systems Models Dataverse</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/08/22/open-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/08/22/open-data/</guid>
      <description>To facilitate the sharing of model data by the Australian mental health modelling community, Acumen curates an open access data repository. The data repository is the Australian Mental Health Systems Models Dataverse.
If you have data from a mental health modelling project that you would like to share via this repository, check out this tutorial about how to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Australian Mental Health Systems Models Zenodo Community</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/08/22/open-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/08/22/open-code/</guid>
      <description>To facilitate the sharing of model code by the Australian mental health modelling community, Acumen curates an open access code repository. The code repository is the Australian Mental Health Systems Models Zenodo Community.
Linked to this repository is Acumen&amp;rsquo;s GitHub organisation. Currently our GitHub organisation is just used to host the source code for this website, but over time we aim to use it to share brief code snippets that may not be appropriate for archiving in our Zenodo repository.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
