<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prevention on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Models</title>
    <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/tags/prevention/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prevention on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Models</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 14:07:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.acumen-mh.org/tags/prevention/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mental health: build predictive models to steer policy</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/09/26/occhipintijmental2021s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 14:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/09/26/occhipintijmental2021s/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Occhipinti, Jo-An and Skinner, Adam and Doraiswamy, P. Murali and Fox, Cameron and Herrman, Helen and Saxena, Shekhar and London, Elisha and Song, Yun Ju Christine and Hickie, Ian B.
Publication: Nature.
Year: 2021
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1038/d41586-021-02581-9
Method: Commentary.
Message: Systems modelling has potential to assist global decision-makers to make proactive economic, social, public health, and health system investments to arrest the COVID pandemic’s impacts on mental health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regional suicide prevention planning: a dynamic simulation modelling analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/08/31/skinneraregional2021q/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 05:35:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/08/31/skinneraregional2021q/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Skinner, Adam and Occhipinti, Jo-An and Song, Yun Ju Christine and Hickie, Ian B.
Publication: BJPsych Open.
Year: 2021
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1192/bjo.2021.989
Method: A systems dynamics model for 10 Primary Health Networks (PHNs) in New South Wales that serve regions that vary in terms of population size, geographic area, population density, levels of disadvantage and suicide rates.
Message: There is potential for substantial variation in projected reductions in suicide mortality if implementing a standardised state-based suicide prevention strategy versus a regionally driven approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Federal and state cooperation necessary but not sufficient for effective regional mental health systems: insights from systems modelling and simulation</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/05/21/occhipintij2021a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/05/21/occhipintij2021a/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Occhipinti, Jo-An and Skinner, Adam and Carter, Samantha and Heath, Jacinta and Lawson, Kenny and McGill, Katherine and McClure, Rod and Hickie, Ian B.
Publication: Scientific Reports.
Year: 2021
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-90762-x
Method: A system dynamics model of pathways between psychological distress, the mental health care system, suicidal behaviour and their drivers was developed, tested, and validated for a large, geographically diverse region of New South Wales; the Hunter New England and Central Coast Primary Health Network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
