<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Epidemiology on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Models</title>
    <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/tags/epidemiology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Epidemiology on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Models</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 21:29:20 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.acumen-mh.org/tags/epidemiology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>National Mental Health Service Planning Framework - Planning Support Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2022/08/22/nmhpft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2022/08/22/nmhpft/</guid>
      <description>Purpose: To estimate need and expected demand for mental health care and the level and mix of mental health services required for a given population.
Type: Tableau user interface to a needs based planning model.
Release status: Production release (V4.0).
Intended users: Mental health planners working in licensed organisations (typically State and Territory Government departments, Local Hospital Networks and Primary Health Networks).
Who can access it?: Intended users in licensed organisations can apply to be trained on using NMHSPF-PST.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound Decision Making in Uncertain Times: Can Systems Modelling Be Useful for Informing Policy and Planning for Suicide Prevention?</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2022/01/28/occhipintijsound2022s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 02:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2022/01/28/occhipintijsound2022s/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Occhipinti, Jo-An and Rose, Danya and Skinner, Adam and Rock, Daniel and Song, Yun Ju C. and Prodan, Ante and Rosenberg, Sebastian and Freebairn, Louise and Vacher, Catherine and Hickie, Ian B.
Publication: International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health.
Year: 2022
DOI: https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph19031468
Method: A systems dynamics model for Western Australia was run for multiple competing scenarios.
Message: Systems models can inform robust decision making despite uncertainty about the trajectories of population mental health outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A modelling tool for policy analysis to support the design of efficient and effective policy responses for complex public health problems</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2015/03/02/atkinsonja2015s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 04:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2015/03/02/atkinsonja2015s/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Atkinson, Jo-An and Page, Andrew and Wells, Robert and Milat, Andrew and Wilson, Andrew
Publication: Implementation Science.
Year: 2015
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1186/s13012-015-0221-5
Method: Commentary.
Message: There is a strong case for inclusion of systems modelling in the analytic tool kit for identifying targeted investments likely to deliver efficient, effective &amp;amp; equitable impacts.
BibTeX: @article{AtkinsonJA2015S, title={A modelling tool for policy analysis to support the design of efficient and effective policy responses for complex public health problems}, author={Atkinson, Jo-An and Page, Andrew and Wells, Robert and Milat, Andrew and Wilson, Andrew}, journal={Implementation Science}, volume={10}, pages={26}, year={2015}, publisher={Springer Science and Business Media LLC}}</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
