<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Complexity Theory on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Modelling</title>
    <link>/tags/complexity-theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Complexity Theory on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Modelling</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 21:29:20 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/complexity-theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The science of complex systems is needed to ameliorate the impacts of COVID-19 on mental health</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/11/25/atkinsonj2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/11/25/atkinsonj2020/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Atkinson, Jo-An and Song, Yun Ju Christine and Merikangas, Kathleen R and Skinner, Adam and Prodan, Ante and Iorfino, Frank and Freebairn, Louise and Rose, Danya and Ho, Nicholas and Crouse, Jacob and Zipunnikov, Vadim and Hickie, Ian.
Publication: Frontiers in Psychiatry.
Year: 2020
DOI: https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyt.2020.606035
Method: Editorial.
Message: Applications of systems modeling in mental health research and practice have already demonstrated value in providing improved decision support capability and a better understanding of the different ways even “evidence-based” interventions can play out in diverse systems and settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factors affecting the implementation of simulation modelling in healthcare: A longitudinal case study evaluation</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/08/20/longk2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/08/20/longk2020/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Long, Katrina M and McDermott, F and Meadows, Graham N
Publication: Journal of the Operational Research Society
Year: 2020
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1080/01605682.2019.1650624
Method: A qualitative, longitudinal case study approach, grounded in Pragmatism, complexity theory, and the critical incident approach exploring implementation of simulation modelling in healthcare.
Message: Twenty-three critical incidents were identified, including changes in government policy and funding, organisational context, intervention activities, project management, and staffing. The analysis revealed a complex adaptive system, where the role of specific implementation factors changed over time, and through interaction with each other.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
