<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SYSTEMS DYNAMICS MODELS on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Models</title>
    <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/tags/systems-dynamics-models/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SYSTEMS DYNAMICS MODELS on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Models</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 02:59:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.acumen-mh.org/tags/systems-dynamics-models/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sound Decision Making in Uncertain Times: Can Systems Modelling Be Useful for Informing Policy and Planning for Suicide Prevention?</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2022/01/28/occhipintijsound2022s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 02:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2022/01/28/occhipintijsound2022s/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Occhipinti, Jo-An and Rose, Danya and Skinner, Adam and Rock, Daniel and Song, Yun Ju C. and Prodan, Ante and Rosenberg, Sebastian and Freebairn, Louise and Vacher, Catherine and Hickie, Ian B.
Publication: International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health.
Year: 2022
DOI: https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph19031468
Method: A systems dynamics model for Western Australia was run for multiple competing scenarios.
Message: Systems models can inform robust decision making despite uncertainty about the trajectories of population mental health outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental health: build predictive models to steer policy</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/09/26/occhipintijmental2021s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 14:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/09/26/occhipintijmental2021s/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Occhipinti, Jo-An and Skinner, Adam and Doraiswamy, P. Murali and Fox, Cameron and Herrman, Helen and Saxena, Shekhar and London, Elisha and Song, Yun Ju Christine and Hickie, Ian B.
Publication: Nature.
Year: 2021
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1038/d41586-021-02581-9
Method: Commentary.
Message: Systems modelling has potential to assist global decision-makers to make proactive economic, social, public health, and health system investments to arrest the COVID pandemic’s impacts on mental health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regional suicide prevention planning: a dynamic simulation modelling analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/08/31/skinneraregional2021q/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 05:35:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/08/31/skinneraregional2021q/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Skinner, Adam and Occhipinti, Jo-An and Song, Yun Ju Christine and Hickie, Ian B.
Publication: BJPsych Open.
Year: 2021
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1192/bjo.2021.989
Method: A systems dynamics model for 10 Primary Health Networks (PHNs) in New South Wales that serve regions that vary in terms of population size, geographic area, population density, levels of disadvantage and suicide rates.
Message: There is potential for substantial variation in projected reductions in suicide mortality if implementing a standardised state-based suicide prevention strategy versus a regionally driven approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A modelling tool for policy analysis to support the design of efficient and effective policy responses for complex public health problems</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2015/03/02/atkinsonja2015s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 04:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2015/03/02/atkinsonja2015s/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Atkinson, Jo-An and Page, Andrew and Wells, Robert and Milat, Andrew and Wilson, Andrew
Publication: Implementation Science.
Year: 2015
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1186/s13012-015-0221-5
Method: Commentary.
Message: There is a strong case for inclusion of systems modelling in the analytic tool kit for identifying targeted investments likely to deliver efficient, effective &amp;amp; equitable impacts.
BibTeX: @article{AtkinsonJA2015S, title={A modelling tool for policy analysis to support the design of efficient and effective policy responses for complex public health problems}, author={Atkinson, Jo-An and Page, Andrew and Wells, Robert and Milat, Andrew and Wilson, Andrew}, journal={Implementation Science}, volume={10}, pages={26}, year={2015}, publisher={Springer Science and Business Media LLC}}</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
