<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Healthcare Improvement on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Models</title>
    <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/tags/healthcare-improvement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Healthcare Improvement on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Models</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 21:29:20 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.acumen-mh.org/tags/healthcare-improvement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Engaging Healthcare Staff and Stakeholders in Healthcare Simulation Modelling for Research Translation: A Systematic Review</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/11/23/zabellt2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/11/23/zabellt2021/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Zabell, Thea Simone and Long, Katrina M and Scott, Debbie and Hope, Judith and McLoughlin, Ian and Enticott, Joanne.
Publication: Frontiers in Health Services.
Year: 2021
DOI: https://doi.org/10.3389/frhs.2021.644831
Method: A systematic review on simulation modelling studies with a health outcome which engaged stakeholders in model design.
Message: There is a large gap in the current literature of formal evaluation of simulation modelling stakeholder engagement, and a lack of consensus about the processes required for effective simulation modelling stakeholder engagement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regional planning for meaningful person-centred care in mental health: context is the signal not the noise</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2017/12/01/rockd2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2017/12/01/rockd2020/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Rock, D and Cross, SP
Publication: Epidemiology and Psychiatric Sciences
Year: 2020
DOI: doi:10.1017/S2045796020000153
Method: Editorial.
Message: To ensure planned and provided care is most appropriate to more than merely the ‘average’ person requires a combination of (1) relevant, local and sophisticated data planning, collection and analysis systems, (2) more detailed person-centred service planning and delivery and (3) system accountability through co-design and transparent public reporting of health system performance in a manner that is understandable, relevant, and locally applicable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
