<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rural Mental Health on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Models</title>
    <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/tags/rural-mental-health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rural Mental Health on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Models</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 04:44:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.acumen-mh.org/tags/rural-mental-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Patterns of mental healthcare provision in rural areas: A demonstration study in Australia and Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2023/02/06/salinas-perezjpatterns2023u/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 04:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2023/02/06/salinas-perezjpatterns2023u/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Salinas-Perez, Jose A. and Gutierrez-Colosia, Mencia R. and Garcia-Alonso, Carlos R. and Furst, Mary Anne and Tabatabaei-Jafari, Hossein and Kalseth, Jorid and Perkins, David and Rosen, Alan and Rock, Daniel and Salvador-Carulla, Luis
Publication: Frontiers in Psychiatry.
Year: 2023
DOI: https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyt.2023.993197
Method: Mental health services in three countries were described and classified using the Description and Evaluation of Services and Directories of Long Term Care mapping tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems modelling and simulation to inform strategic decision making for suicide prevention in rural New South Wales (Australia)</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2020/06/17/atkinsonj2020b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2020/06/17/atkinsonj2020b/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Atkinson, Jo-An and Skinner, Adam and Hackney, Sue and Mason, Linda and Heffernan, Mark and Currier, Dianne and King, Kylie and Pirkis, Jane.
Publication: Australian and New Zealand Journal of Psychiatry.
Year 2020
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1177/0004867420932639
Method: A system dynamics model for the rural and remote population catchment of Western New South Wales was developed. The model was based on defined pathways to mental health care and suicidal behaviour and reproduced historic trends in the incidence of attempted suicide (self-harm hospitalisations) and suicide deaths in the region.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
