<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DATA VISUALISATION on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Models</title>
    <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/tags/data-visualisation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DATA VISUALISATION on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Models</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 21:29:20 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.acumen-mh.org/tags/data-visualisation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Experts’ perceptions on the use of visual analytics for complex mental healthcare planning: an exploratory study</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2020/05/07/walshe2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2020/05/07/walshe2020/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Walsh, Erin I and Chung, Younjin and Cherbuin, Nicolas and Salvador-Carulla, Luis.
Publication: BMC Medical Research Methodology
Year: 2020
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1186/s12874-020-00986-0
Method: Online survey of an international pool of policy-makers, health agency directors, and researchers with extensive and direct experience of using visual analytics tools for complex mental healthcare systems planning.
Message: Preliminary findings indicated that, despite a clear need to extract information from highly complex data, experts tend to utilise visualisations that are most familiar to them, widely understood, and not necessarily the most appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of visual analytics in supporting mental healthcare systems research and policy: A systematic scoping review</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2019/05/10/chungyrole2020u/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 17:27:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2019/05/10/chungyrole2020u/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Chung, Younjin and Bagheri, Nasser and Salinas-Perez, Jose Alberto and Smurthwaite, Kayla and Walsh, Erin and Furst, MaryAnne and Rosenberg, Sebastian and Salvador-Carulla, Luis
Publication: International Journal of Information Management.
Year: 2020
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijinfomgt.2019.04.012
Method: Scoping review.
Message: Visual analytics is needed for mental healthcare systems research and policy.
BibTeX: @article{ChungYRole2020U, title={Role of visual analytics in supporting mental healthcare systems research and policy: A systematic scoping review}, author={Chung, Younjin and Bagheri, Nasser and Salinas-Perez, Jose Alberto and Smurthwaite, Kayla and Walsh, Erin and Furst, MaryAnne and Rosenberg, Sebastian and Salvador-Carulla, Luis}, journal={International Journal of Information Management}, volume={50}, pages={}, year={2020}, publisher={Elsevier BV}}</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
