<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Models</title>
    <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/our-work/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Models</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 21:29:20 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/our-work/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mental health systems modelling for evidence-informed service reform in Australia</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2023/05/14/whitefordh2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2023/05/14/whitefordh2022/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Whiteford, Harvey and Bagheri, Nasser and Diminic, Sandra and Enticott, Joanne and Gao, Caroline X and Hamilton, Matthew and Hickie, Ian and Le, Long K and Lee, Yong Y and Long, Katrina M and McGorry, Patrick and Meadows, Graham and Mihalopoulos, Cathrine and Occhipinti, Jo-An and Rock, Daniel and Rosenberg, Sebastian and Salvador-Carulla, Luis and Skinner, Adam.
Publication: PsyArXiv
Year: 2023
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1177/00048674231172113
Method: Descriptive overview of the role of modelling in mental health policy and system design, explanation of concepts useful for understanding mental health modelling and overview of how ta new network of modellers and planners hopes to support the development of better and more useful mental health systems models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patterns of mental healthcare provision in rural areas: A demonstration study in Australia and Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2023/02/06/salinas-perezjpatterns2023u/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 04:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2023/02/06/salinas-perezjpatterns2023u/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Salinas-Perez, Jose A. and Gutierrez-Colosia, Mencia R. and Garcia-Alonso, Carlos R. and Furst, Mary Anne and Tabatabaei-Jafari, Hossein and Kalseth, Jorid and Perkins, David and Rosen, Alan and Rock, Daniel and Salvador-Carulla, Luis
Publication: Frontiers in Psychiatry.
Year: 2023
DOI: https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyt.2023.993197
Method: Mental health services in three countries were described and classified using the Description and Evaluation of Services and Directories of Long Term Care mapping tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound Decision Making in Uncertain Times: Can Systems Modelling Be Useful for Informing Policy and Planning for Suicide Prevention?</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2022/01/28/occhipintijsound2022s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 02:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2022/01/28/occhipintijsound2022s/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Occhipinti, Jo-An and Rose, Danya and Skinner, Adam and Rock, Daniel and Song, Yun Ju C. and Prodan, Ante and Rosenberg, Sebastian and Freebairn, Louise and Vacher, Catherine and Hickie, Ian B.
Publication: International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health.
Year: 2022
DOI: https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph19031468
Method: A systems dynamics model for Western Australia was run for multiple competing scenarios.
Message: Systems models can inform robust decision making despite uncertainty about the trajectories of population mental health outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engaging Healthcare Staff and Stakeholders in Healthcare Simulation Modelling for Research Translation: A Systematic Review</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/11/23/zabellt2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/11/23/zabellt2021/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Zabell, Thea Simone and Long, Katrina M and Scott, Debbie and Hope, Judith and McLoughlin, Ian and Enticott, Joanne.
Publication: Frontiers in Health Services.
Year: 2021
DOI: https://doi.org/10.3389/frhs.2021.644831
Method: A systematic review on simulation modelling studies with a health outcome which engaged stakeholders in model design.
Message: There is a large gap in the current literature of formal evaluation of simulation modelling stakeholder engagement, and a lack of consensus about the processes required for effective simulation modelling stakeholder engagement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental health: build predictive models to steer policy</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/09/26/occhipintijmental2021s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 14:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/09/26/occhipintijmental2021s/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Occhipinti, Jo-An and Skinner, Adam and Doraiswamy, P. Murali and Fox, Cameron and Herrman, Helen and Saxena, Shekhar and London, Elisha and Song, Yun Ju Christine and Hickie, Ian B.
Publication: Nature.
Year: 2021
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1038/d41586-021-02581-9
Method: Commentary.
Message: Systems modelling has potential to assist global decision-makers to make proactive economic, social, public health, and health system investments to arrest the COVID pandemic’s impacts on mental health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regional suicide prevention planning: a dynamic simulation modelling analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/08/31/skinneraregional2021q/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 05:35:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/08/31/skinneraregional2021q/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Skinner, Adam and Occhipinti, Jo-An and Song, Yun Ju Christine and Hickie, Ian B.
Publication: BJPsych Open.
Year: 2021
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1192/bjo.2021.989
Method: A systems dynamics model for 10 Primary Health Networks (PHNs) in New South Wales that serve regions that vary in terms of population size, geographic area, population density, levels of disadvantage and suicide rates.
Message: There is potential for substantial variation in projected reductions in suicide mortality if implementing a standardised state-based suicide prevention strategy versus a regionally driven approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Federal and state cooperation necessary but not sufficient for effective regional mental health systems: insights from systems modelling and simulation</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/05/21/occhipintij2021a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/05/21/occhipintij2021a/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Occhipinti, Jo-An and Skinner, Adam and Carter, Samantha and Heath, Jacinta and Lawson, Kenny and McGill, Katherine and McClure, Rod and Hickie, Ian B.
Publication: Scientific Reports.
Year: 2021
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-90762-x
Method: A system dynamics model of pathways between psychological distress, the mental health care system, suicidal behaviour and their drivers was developed, tested, and validated for a large, geographically diverse region of New South Wales; the Hunter New England and Central Coast Primary Health Network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing youth suicide: systems modelling and simulation to guide targeted investments across the determinants</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/03/12/occhipintij2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2021/03/12/occhipintij2021/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Occhipinti, Jo-An and Skinner, Adam and Iorfino, Frank and Lawson, Kenny and Sturgess, Julie and Burgess, Warren and Davenport, Tracey and Hudson, Danica and Hickie, Ian.
Publication: BMC Medicine.
Year: 2021
DOI: https://bmcmedicine.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12916-021-01935-4
Method: Using a participatory approach, and informed by a range of national, state, and local datasets, a system dynamics model was developed, tested, and validated for a regional population catchment. The model incorporated defined pathways from social determinants of mental health to psychological distress, mental health care, and suicidal behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The science of complex systems is needed to ameliorate the impacts of COVID-19 on mental health</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2020/11/25/atkinsonj2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2020/11/25/atkinsonj2020/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Atkinson, Jo-An and Song, Yun Ju Christine and Merikangas, Kathleen R and Skinner, Adam and Prodan, Ante and Iorfino, Frank and Freebairn, Louise and Rose, Danya and Ho, Nicholas and Crouse, Jacob and Zipunnikov, Vadim and Hickie, Ian.
Publication: Frontiers in Psychiatry.
Year: 2020
DOI: https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyt.2020.606035
Method: Editorial.
Message: Applications of systems modeling in mental health research and practice have already demonstrated value in providing improved decision support capability and a better understanding of the different ways even “evidence-based” interventions can play out in diverse systems and settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The National Mental Health Service Planning Framework: Where has it come from and what is its future?</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2020/11/02/whitefordh2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2020/11/02/whitefordh2020/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Whiteford, Harvey and Diminic, Sandra.
Publication: Australian and New Zealand Journal of Psychiatry
Year: 2020
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1177/0004867420963723
Method: Descriptive account of the background and application of the National Mental Health Service Planning Framework.
Message: Decentralised regional planning requires the application of a planning framework that sets targets for the same level of care for all Australians with equivalent needs, accounting for the specific characteristics and needs of local populations and the existing services and barriers to care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems modelling and simulation to inform strategic decision making for suicide prevention in rural New South Wales (Australia)</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2020/06/17/atkinsonj2020b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2020/06/17/atkinsonj2020b/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Atkinson, Jo-An and Skinner, Adam and Hackney, Sue and Mason, Linda and Heffernan, Mark and Currier, Dianne and King, Kylie and Pirkis, Jane.
Publication: Australian and New Zealand Journal of Psychiatry.
Year 2020
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1177/0004867420932639
Method: A system dynamics model for the rural and remote population catchment of Western New South Wales was developed. The model was based on defined pathways to mental health care and suicidal behaviour and reproduced historic trends in the incidence of attempted suicide (self-harm hospitalisations) and suicide deaths in the region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experts’ perceptions on the use of visual analytics for complex mental healthcare planning: an exploratory study</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2020/05/07/walshe2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2020/05/07/walshe2020/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Walsh, Erin I and Chung, Younjin and Cherbuin, Nicolas and Salvador-Carulla, Luis.
Publication: BMC Medical Research Methodology
Year: 2020
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1186/s12874-020-00986-0
Method: Online survey of an international pool of policy-makers, health agency directors, and researchers with extensive and direct experience of using visual analytics tools for complex mental healthcare systems planning.
Message: Preliminary findings indicated that, despite a clear need to extract information from highly complex data, experts tend to utilise visualisations that are most familiar to them, widely understood, and not necessarily the most appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An ecosystems approach to mental health services research</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2020/03/24/furstm2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2020/03/24/furstm2021/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Furst, Mary Anne and Bagheri, Nasser and Salvador-Carulla, Luis}
Publication: BJPsych International
Year: 2020
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1192/bji.2020.24
Method: Descriptive summary of mental health ecosystems methods.
Message: Mental health ecosystems research is an emerging discipline which takes a whole-systems approach to mental healthcare, facilitating analysis of the complex environment and context of mental health systems, and translation of this knowledge into policy and practice. Evidence from the local context is needed in the analysis of complex interventions and of geographic variations in the outcomes of care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factors affecting the implementation of simulation modelling in healthcare: A longitudinal case study evaluation</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2019/08/20/longk2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2019/08/20/longk2020/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Long, Katrina M and McDermott, F and Meadows, Graham N
Publication: Journal of the Operational Research Society
Year: 2020
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1080/01605682.2019.1650624
Method: A qualitative, longitudinal case study approach, grounded in Pragmatism, complexity theory, and the critical incident approach exploring implementation of simulation modelling in healthcare.
Message: Twenty-three critical incidents were identified, including changes in government policy and funding, organisational context, intervention activities, project management, and staffing. The analysis revealed a complex adaptive system, where the role of specific implementation factors changed over time, and through interaction with each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of reducing psychiatric beds on suicide rates</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2019/07/02/atkinsonj2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2019/07/02/atkinsonj2021/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Atkinson, Jo-An and Page, Andrew and Skinner, Adam and Heffernan, Mark and Prodan, Ante and Hickie, Ian B.
Publication: Frontiers in Psychiatry.
Year: 2019
DOI: https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyt.2019.00448
Method: A systems dynamics model was developed for Western Sydney Primary Health Network.
Message: Study findings suggest that i) not all reductions to psychiatric beds will result in increases in suicide deaths; ii) a threshold appears to exist beyond which cuts are likely to adversely impact suicides; and iii) the threshold can be significantly increased by strengthening community-based mental health services capacity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of visual analytics in supporting mental healthcare systems research and policy: A systematic scoping review</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2019/05/10/chungyrole2020u/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 17:27:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2019/05/10/chungyrole2020u/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Chung, Younjin and Bagheri, Nasser and Salinas-Perez, Jose Alberto and Smurthwaite, Kayla and Walsh, Erin and Furst, MaryAnne and Rosenberg, Sebastian and Salvador-Carulla, Luis
Publication: International Journal of Information Management.
Year: 2020
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijinfomgt.2019.04.012
Method: Scoping review.
Message: Visual analytics is needed for mental healthcare systems research and policy.
BibTeX: @article{ChungYRole2020U, title={Role of visual analytics in supporting mental healthcare systems research and policy: A systematic scoping review}, author={Chung, Younjin and Bagheri, Nasser and Salinas-Perez, Jose Alberto and Smurthwaite, Kayla and Walsh, Erin and Furst, MaryAnne and Rosenberg, Sebastian and Salvador-Carulla, Luis}, journal={International Journal of Information Management}, volume={50}, pages={}, year={2020}, publisher={Elsevier BV}}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A decision support system for assessing management interventions in a mental health ecosystem: The case of Bizkaia (Basque Country, Spain)</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2019/02/14/garc%C3%ADa-alonsoca2019u/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 18:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2019/02/14/garc%C3%ADa-alonsoca2019u/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: García-Alonso, Carlos R. and Almeda, Nerea and Salinas-Pérez, José A. and Gutiérrez-Colosía, Mencía R. and Uriarte-Uriarte, José J. and Salvador-Carulla, Luis
Publication: PLOS ONE.
Year: 2019
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0212179
Method: A Monte-Carlo simulation combined with a fuzzy inference engine was used to examine the Relative Technical Efficiency (RTE) of three proposed intervention scenarios.
Message: Decision makers can use information from this approach to design new interventions and policies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causal modelling for supporting planning and management of mental health services and systems: a systematic review</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2019/01/25/almeda2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2019/01/25/almeda2019/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Almeda, Nerea and García-Alonso, Carlos R and Salinas-Pérez, José A and Gutiérrez-Colosía, Mencía R and Salvador-Carulla, Luis.
Publication: International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health.
Year: 2019
DOI: https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph16030332
Method: A systematic review the use of causal modelling (a tool for decision-making based on identifying critical variables and their causal relationships) in mental health services and systems.
Message: The papers included in the review showed very different objectives and subjects of study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regional planning for meaningful person-centred care in mental health: context is the signal not the noise</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2017/12/01/rockd2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2017/12/01/rockd2020/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Rock, D and Cross, SP
Publication: Epidemiology and Psychiatric Sciences
Year: 2020
DOI: doi:10.1017/S2045796020000153
Method: Editorial.
Message: To ensure planned and provided care is most appropriate to more than merely the ‘average’ person requires a combination of (1) relevant, local and sophisticated data planning, collection and analysis systems, (2) more detailed person-centred service planning and delivery and (3) system accountability through co-design and transparent public reporting of health system performance in a manner that is understandable, relevant, and locally applicable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulation modelling in mental health: A systematic review</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2017/12/01/longk2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2017/12/01/longk2018/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Long, Katrina M and Meadows, Graham N
Publication: Journal of Simulation
Year: 2018
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1057/s41273-017-0062-0
Method: A systematic review the use of simulation modelling in mental healthcare.
Message: There were widespread and innovative applications of simulation in the areas of medical decision making and epidemiology, with health system planning and optimisation relatively underrepresented. Markov modelling was the preferred method across area and illness. However, the literature is currently undermined by a lack of coherence and evidence of implementation, and there is an ongoing issue of accessing unpublished models from healthcare and government organisations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A modelling tool for policy analysis to support the design of efficient and effective policy responses for complex public health problems</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2015/03/02/atkinsonja2015s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 04:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2015/03/02/atkinsonja2015s/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Atkinson, Jo-An and Page, Andrew and Wells, Robert and Milat, Andrew and Wilson, Andrew
Publication: Implementation Science.
Year: 2015
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1186/s13012-015-0221-5
Method: Commentary.
Message: There is a strong case for inclusion of systems modelling in the analytic tool kit for identifying targeted investments likely to deliver efficient, effective &amp;amp; equitable impacts.
BibTeX: @article{AtkinsonJA2015S, title={A modelling tool for policy analysis to support the design of efficient and effective policy responses for complex public health problems}, author={Atkinson, Jo-An and Page, Andrew and Wells, Robert and Milat, Andrew and Wilson, Andrew}, journal={Implementation Science}, volume={10}, pages={26}, year={2015}, publisher={Springer Science and Business Media LLC}}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating clinicians, knowledge and data: expert-based cooperative analysis in healthcare decision support</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2010/09/30/gilbertk2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2010/09/30/gilbertk2010/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Gibert, Karina and García-Alonso, Carlos and Salvador-Carulla, Luis
Publication: Health research policy and systems
Year: 2010
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1186/1478-4505-8-28
Method: Descriptive introduction of a new hybrid methodology Expert-based Cooperative Analysis (EbCA), which incorporates explicit prior expert knowledge in data analysis methods, and elicits implicit or tacit expert knowledge to improve decision support in healthcare systems. EbCA was compared to classical procedures using qualitative explicit prior knowledge in two case examples: 1) Bench-marking of small mental health areas based on technical efficiency estimated by EbCA-Data Envelopment Analysis (EbCA-DEA), and 2) Case-mix of schizophrenia based on functional dependency using Clustering Based on Rules (ClBR).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources for mental health: scarcity, inequity, and inefficiency</title>
      <link>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2007/12/01/saxenas2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2007 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.acumen-mh.org/blog/2007/12/01/saxenas2007/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Saxena, Shekhar and Thornicroft, Graham and Knapp, Martin and Whiteford, Harvey.
Publication: The Lancet.
Year: 2007
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(07)61239-2
Method: Narrative review and discussion of the international availability of resources for mental health, including policy and infrastructure within countries, mental health services, community resources, human resources, and funding.
Message: Government spending on mental health in most of the relevant countries is far lower than is needed, based on the proportionate burden of mental disorders and the availability of cost-effective and affordable interventions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
