<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>System Dynamics Models on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Modelling</title>
    <link>/tags/system-dynamics-models/</link>
    <description>Recent content in System Dynamics Models on Acumen - Alliance for Mental Health Systems Modelling</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 21:29:20 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/system-dynamics-models/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Federal and state cooperation necessary but not sufficient for effective regional mental health systems: insights from systems modelling and simulation</title>
      <link>/blog/2021/05/21/occhipintij2021a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021/05/21/occhipintij2021a/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Occhipinti, Jo-An and Skinner, Adam and Carter, Samantha and Heath, Jacinta and Lawson, Kenny and McGill, Katherine and McClure, Rod and Hickie, Ian B.
Publication: Scientific Reports.
Year: 2021
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-90762-x
Method: A system dynamics model of pathways between psychological distress, the mental health care system, suicidal behaviour and their drivers was developed, tested, and validated for a large, geographically diverse region of New South Wales; the Hunter New England and Central Coast Primary Health Network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing youth suicide: systems modelling and simulation to guide targeted investments across the determinants</title>
      <link>/blog/2021/03/12/occhipintij2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021/03/12/occhipintij2021/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Occhipinti, Jo-An and Skinner, Adam and Iorfino, Frank and Lawson, Kenny and Sturgess, Julie and Burgess, Warren and Davenport, Tracey and Hudson, Danica and Hickie, Ian.
Publication: BMC Medicine.
Year: 2021
DOI: https://bmcmedicine.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12916-021-01935-4
Method: Using a participatory approach, and informed by a range of national, state, and local datasets, a system dynamics model was developed, tested, and validated for a regional population catchment. The model incorporated defined pathways from social determinants of mental health to psychological distress, mental health care, and suicidal behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems modelling and simulation to inform strategic decision making for suicide prevention in rural New South Wales (Australia)</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/06/17/atkinsonj2020b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/06/17/atkinsonj2020b/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Atkinson, Jo-An and Skinner, Adam and Hackney, Sue and Mason, Linda and Heffernan, Mark and Currier, Dianne and King, Kylie and Pirkis, Jane.
Publication: Australian and New Zealand Journal of Psychiatry.
Year 2020
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1177/0004867420932639
Method: A system dynamics model for the rural and remote population catchment of Western New South Wales was developed. The model was based on defined pathways to mental health care and suicidal behaviour and reproduced historic trends in the incidence of attempted suicide (self-harm hospitalisations) and suicide deaths in the region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impact of reducing psychiatric beds on suicide rates</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/07/02/atkinsonj2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/07/02/atkinsonj2021/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Atkinson, Jo-An and Page, Andrew and Skinner, Adam and Heffernan, Mark and Prodan, Ante and Hickie, Ian B.
Publication: Frontiers in Psychiatry.
Year: 2019
DOI: https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyt.2019.00448
Method: A systems dynamics model was developed for Western Sydney Primary Health Network.
Message: Study findings suggest that i) not all reductions to psychiatric beds will result in increases in suicide deaths; ii) a threshold appears to exist beyond which cuts are likely to adversely impact suicides; and iii) the threshold can be significantly increased by strengthening community-based mental health services capacity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
