<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uses of Modelling on National Mental Health Systems Modelling Network</title>
    <link>/tags/uses-of-modelling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uses of Modelling on National Mental Health Systems Modelling Network</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 21:29:20 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/uses-of-modelling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using systems modelling for evidence-informed mental health reform in Australia.</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/08/27/first-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/08/27/first-paper/</guid>
      <description>To introduce the National Mental Health Systems Modelling Network, members pooled their expertise to draft an article about the role of systems modelling in Australian mental health reform processes. The article provides an overview of current and previous mental health reform plans in Australia, identifies and describes different modelling approaches and the types of topics they are particularly well suited to addressing and discusses challenges and opportunities for planners and policymakers relating to the commissioning, development and use of model based tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engaging Healthcare Staff and Stakeholders in Healthcare Simulation Modelling for Research Translation: A Systematic Review</title>
      <link>/blog/2021/11/23/zabellt2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021/11/23/zabellt2021/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Zabell, Thea Simone and Long, Katrina M and Scott, Debbie and Hope, Judith and McLoughlin, Ian and Enticott, Joanne.
Publication: Frontiers in Health Services.
Year: 2021
DOI: https://doi.org/10.3389/frhs.2021.644831
Method: A systematic review on simulation modelling studies with a health outcome which engaged stakeholders in model design.
Message: There is a large gap in the current literature of formal evaluation of simulation modelling stakeholder engagement, and a lack of consensus about the processes required for effective simulation modelling stakeholder engagement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The science of complex systems is needed to ameliorate the impacts of COVID-19 on mental health</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/11/25/atkinsonj2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/11/25/atkinsonj2020/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Atkinson, Jo-An and Song, Yun Ju Christine and Merikangas, Kathleen R and Skinner, Adam and Prodan, Ante and Iorfino, Frank and Freebairn, Louise and Rose, Danya and Ho, Nicholas and Crouse, Jacob and Zipunnikov, Vadim and Hickie, Ian.
Publication: Frontiers in Psychiatry.
Year: 2020
DOI: https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyt.2020.606035
Method: Editorial.
Message: Applications of systems modeling in mental health research and practice have already demonstrated value in providing improved decision support capability and a better understanding of the different ways even “evidence-based” interventions can play out in diverse systems and settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The National Mental Health Service Planning Framework: Where has it come from and what is its future?</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/11/02/whitefordh2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/11/02/whitefordh2020/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Whiteford, Harvey and Diminic, Sandra.
Publication: Australian and New Zealand Journal of Psychiatry
Year: 2020
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1177/0004867420963723
Method: Descriptive account of the background and application of the National Mental Health Service Planning Framework.
Message: Decentralised regional planning requires the application of a planning framework that sets targets for the same level of care for all Australians with equivalent needs, accounting for the specific characteristics and needs of local populations and the existing services and barriers to care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond prevention: which interventions will flatten the mental health and suicide curve post COVID-19.</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/05/14/covid-sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/05/14/covid-sky/</guid>
      <description>Year: 2020
Type: Webinar
Presenters: Hickie, Ian and Occhipinti, Jo-An and Sturgess, Julie and Iorfino, Frank and Lawson, Kenny and Hamilton, Matthew
Institution: Brain and Mind Centre, University of Sydney
Topic: An overview of a number of modelling projects to help identify appropriate policy responses to the anticipated mental health impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic.
Duration: 1 hour, 12 minutes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causal modelling for supporting planning and management of mental health services and systems: a systematic review</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/01/25/almeda2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/01/25/almeda2019/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes.
Authors: Almeda, Nerea and García-Alonso, Carlos R and Salinas-Pérez, José A and Gutiérrez-Colosía, Mencía R and Salvador-Carulla, Luis.
Publication: International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health.
Year: 2019
DOI: https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph16030332
Method: A systematic review the use of causal modelling (a tool for decision-making based on identifying critical variables and their causal relationships) in mental health services and systems.
Message: The papers included in the review showed very different objectives and subjects of study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulation modelling in mental health: A systematic review</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/12/01/longk2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/12/01/longk2018/</guid>
      <description>Peer reviewed: Yes
Authors: Long, Katrina M and Meadows, Graham N
Publication: Journal of Simulation
Year: 2018
DOI: https://doi.org/10.1057/s41273-017-0062-0
Method: A systematic review the use of simulation modelling in mental healthcare.
Message: There were widespread and innovative applications of simulation in the areas of medical decision making and epidemiology, with health system planning and optimisation relatively underrepresented. Markov modelling was the preferred method across area and illness. However, the literature is currently undermined by a lack of coherence and evidence of implementation, and there is an ongoing issue of accessing unpublished models from healthcare and government organisations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
